<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
                         "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd" [
	<!ENTITY % global_entities SYSTEM "../common/global.ent">
	%global_entities;
]>
<article>
  <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
  <qandaset defaultlabel="qanda">
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What is &esvn;?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>&esvn; is a Graphical User Interface (<acronym>GUI</acronym>) to the &svn;
          revision management system.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What is &svn;?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Rather than explain it all over again here is a quote from a free book <ulink
            url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/">Version Control with Subversion</ulink>. <blockquote>
            <attribution>Version Control with Subversion</attribution>
            <para>&quot;Subversion is a free/open-source version control system. That is,
              Subversion manages files and directories over time. A tree of files is placed into a
              central repository. The repository is much like an ordinary file server, except that
              it remembers every change ever made to your files and directories. This allows you to
              recover older versions of your data, or examine the history of how your data changed.
              In this regard, many people think of a version control system as a sort of
              &quot;time machine&quot;.</para>
            <para>Subversion can access its repository across networks, which allows it to be used
              by people on different computers. At some level, the ability for various people to
              modify and manage the same set of data from their respective locations fosters
              collaboration. Progress can occur more quickly without a single conduit through which
              all modifications must occur. And because the work is versioned, you need not fear
              that quality is the trade-off for losing that conduit—if some incorrect change is made
              to the data, just undo that change.</para>
            <para>Some version control systems are also software configuration management (SCM)
              systems. These systems are specifically tailored to manage trees of source code, and
              have many features that are specific to software development—such as natively
              understanding programming languages, or supplying tools for building software.
              Subversion, however, is not one of these systems. It is a general system that can be
              used to manage any collection of files. For you, those files might be source code—for
              others, anything from grocery shopping lists to digital video mixdowns and beyond.&quot;</para>
          </blockquote>
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I run &esvn; on <trademark>Windows</trademark>?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes. A <application class="software">Win32</application> version of &esvn; is
          available as a binary build.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>I want to contribute. What is the tool-chain used in development?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>The following tool chain is used in the development of &esvn;:</para>
        <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
          <listitem>
            <para>GCC - 3.3.3</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>QT - 3.3</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Visual SlickEdit, KDevelop3</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Debug - gdb (kdbg), ddd</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>The following tool chain is used in the development of &esvn; documentation:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              <ulink url="http://www.docbook.org">Docbook XML</ulink>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Editor - Any XML Editor can be used.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Parser - Xerces-J</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>XSLT Processor - Saxon or Xalan</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>FO Processor - FOP</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What dependencies does &esvn; have?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>&esvn; is dependent on the following: &varlist-requirements; </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>What external diff tools can I use with &esvn;?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Following is a list of diff applications that can be used.
          &varlist-external-diff-tools; </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Command line &svn; prompts for user and password, &esvn; doesn't and I can't get access to my repository. How do I 
          solve this?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Use the &file-options; dialog to specify a user-name and password.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>Can I &apos;bookmark&apos; repositories like a
          web browser bookmarks pages, and associate a unique user-name and password with each
          bookmark?</para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>Yes and no. Instead of &apos;bookmarks&apos; &esvn; uses the other concept -
          &apos;workspaces&apos;. Authentication details are stored together with each workspace so you don't need to save this information for each repository. For more details see the
          &esvn; documentation.</para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
  </qandaset>
</article>
