<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--<!DOCTYPE variablelist PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
                      "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd"[
	<!ENTITY % global_entities SYSTEM "../common/global.ent">
	%global_entities;
]>-->
<variablelist>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">kdiff3</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>KDiff3 is a program that compares or merges two or three text input files or
				directories, showing the differences line by line and character by character. KDiff3
				provides an automatic merge-facility and an integrated editor for comfortable solving of
				merge-conflicts. The program also supports KIO on KDE (allows accessing ftp, sftp, fish, smb
				etc.), and has an intuitive graphical user interface. More information and downloads are
				available from the <ulink url="http://kdiff3.sourceforge.net/">KDiff3 Web Site</ulink>.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">Kompare</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>Kompare is a KDE frontend to the Open Source diff application. Kompare is shipped as
				part of the KDE SDK. More information is available from the <ulink
					url="http://www.kde.org/">KDE Web Site</ulink>.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">xxdiff</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>xxdiff is a graphical file and directories comparator and merge tool. xxdiff is useful
				for comparing two files, three files, or two directories (shallow and recursive). It
				provides horizontal diffs highlighting and files can be merged interactively with
				visualization and saving of the resulting output. xxdiff has features to assist in
				performing merge reviews/policing and can unmerge CVS conflicts in automatically merged file
				and display them as two files, to help resolve conflicts. xxdiff uses external diff programs
				to compute differences: works with GNU diff, SGI diff and ClearCase's cleardiff, and any
				other similar diff tools. More information and downloads can be found at the <ulink
					url="http://xxdiff.sourceforge.net/">xxdiff Web Site</ulink>. </para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">TkDiff</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>TkDiff is a graphical front end to the diff program. It provides a side-by-side view of
				the differences between two files, along with several innovative features such as diff
				bookmarks and a graphical map of differences for quick navigation. More information and
				download can be found on the <ulink url="http://tkdiff.sourceforge.net/">TkDiff Web Site</ulink>.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">GTKdiff</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>GTKdiff is a graphical diff tool. It has diff3 and merge features. It's written with
				GTK+. After gtkdiff-0.8.0, it requires <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/">GNOME</ulink>.
				More information and download can be found the <ulink
					url="http://home.catv.ne.jp/pp/ginoue/software/gtkdiff/index-e.html">GTKdiff Web Site</ulink>.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">Meld</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>Meld is a visual diff and merge tool. It integrates especially well with CVS. The diff
				viewer lets you edit files in place (diffs update dynamically), and a middle column shows
				detailed changes and allows merges. The margins show location of changes for easy
				navigation, and it also features a tabbed interface that allows you to open many diffs at
				once. More information and download can be found the <ulink
					url="http://meld.sourceforge.net/">Meld Web Site</ulink>.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<emphasis role="bold">
				<application class="software">ExamDiff</application>
			</emphasis>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>ExamDiff Pro is a powerful yet intuitive and easy to use visual file and directory
				comparison tool for Windows. It features unique functionality that distinguishes ExamDiff
				Pro from other comparison programs. If you used WinDiff or UNIX diff before, you will find
				that ExamDiff Pro offers much more efficient and user-friendly way to compare files and
				folders. More information and download can be found the <ulink
				url="http://www.prestosoft.com/">PrestoSoft</ulink> the developers of ExamDiff.</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
</variablelist>
