<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd" [
	<!ENTITY % global_entities SYSTEM "../common/global.ent">
	%global_entities;
]>-->
<appendix id="appen-building">
    <title>Building</title>
    <para>Since not all computer operating systems are configured in the same standard way and their
        environments differ, there is a need to build packages that are specifically build to
        accommodate the needs of the various target systems. Many Linux distributions use the Red
        Hat Package Manager as the tool of choice managing packages. This quote explains what RPM is:</para>
    <para>
        <blockquote>
            <attribution>
                <ulink url="http://www.rpm.org">rpm.org</ulink>
            </attribution>
            <para>The RPM Package Manager (RPM) is a powerful command line driven package management
                system capable of installing, uninstalling, verifying, querying, and updating
                computer software packages. Each software package consists of an archive of files
                along with information about the package like its version, a description, and the
                like. There is also a related API (&quot;Application Program
                Interface&quot;), permitting advanced developers to bypass &apos;shelling
                out&apos; to a command line, and to manage such transactions from within a
                native coding language.</para>
        </blockquote>
    </para>
    <para>While RPM is a standard tool for managing software packages it is not necessarily true
        that all software packages made with RPM can be installed on all Linux distributions. The
        reason being is that very often the various &apos;distro&apos; have arranged their
        file and folder systems in ways that are different to greater or lesser degrees, depending
        on which two you compare. As a result it is recommended that a software is installed with a
        RPM that is specifically configured for the target operating system and its environment.</para>
    <para>The tool used to build RPM packages is called <application
        class="software">rpmbuild</application>. It is a command line tool, which is a part of the
        Red Hat Package Manager (RPM), that enables building of the following software package types:</para>
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>
                <emphasis role="bold">binary</emphasis>
            </term>
            <listitem>
                <para>Contains software to be installed</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>
                <emphasis role="bold">source</emphasis>
            </term>
            <listitem>
                <para>Contains the source code and recipe necessary to produce binary packages</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>A package consists of an archive of files and meta-data used to install and erase the
        archive files. The meta-data includes helper scripts, file attributes, and descriptive
        information about the package. So a package holds together all the information required to
        install and uninstall a piece of software.</para>
    <para>This appendix covers only the most basic information needed for package builders. It
        assumes experience with building and testing packages, especially resolving problems to
        configure for the target system. If you wish to build packages for a particular system using
        RPM and need more information about RPM a good resource to read is &quot;<ulink
            url="http://rpm-devel.colug.net/max-rpm/index.html">Maximum RPM</ulink>&quot; by
        Edward C. Bailey, Paul Nasrat, Matthias Saou, Ville Skyttä.</para>
    <para>In combination with this book we give a pretty good overview of how you can build packages
        for &esvn;. However, before you decide to go through all this work you may first want to
        check at the &esvn; <ulink url="http://esvn.umputun.com">Web Site</ulink> to see if
        somebody has already built a package for your system.</para>
    <sect1>
        <title>Prerequisites</title>
        <para>To build &esvn; the following packages and their dependencies must be installed
            and available on the build machine:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>qt3-devel</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>GNU Make</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>RPM</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A copy of the &esvn; sources.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Building a Binary Package</title>
        <para>To build a RPM use the following command. Replace the <varname>VERSION</varname>
            variable with the number of the version.</para>
        <para>
            <command>rpm -ta esvn-$(VERSION)-$(RELEASE).tar.gz</command>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Building from Binary Package with Source RPM</title>
        <para>To build &esvn; from sources with <filename class="extension">rpms</filename> use
            the following.</para>
        <procedure>
            <title>Building from RPM with RPMS</title>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>rpm -Uvh src.rpm</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>rbmbuild -bb /usr/src/packages/SRPMS/esvn.spec</command>
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Building from Source Binary package without Source RPM</title>
        <para>To build &esvn; from sources without <filename class="extension">rpms</filename>
            use the following.</para>
        <procedure>
            <title>Building from RPM without RPMS</title>
            <step>
                <para><command>make clean &amp;&amp; make</command></para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para><command>su -c &quot;make install&quot;</command></para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Using the &esvn; Makefile</title>
        <para>To make life easy, we have created a Makefile that can be used to create tarball
                (<filename class="extension">tar.gz</filename>), binary (<filename
            class="extension">rpm</filename>) and source binary (<filename
            class="extension">rpms</filename>) from the your Working Copy code.</para>
        <procedure>
            <title>Building &esvn; with Make</title>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>cd</command> to the root of your &esvn; working copy directory.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Do <command>svn update</command>.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>cd dist</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make clean</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make prog</command>
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Building the &esvn; Documentation</title>
        <para>It is possible to build the &esvn; documentation in HTML and PDF without building
            the &esvn; program.</para>
        <procedure>
            <title>Building the &esvn; Documentation</title>
            <step>
                <para>Do <command>svn update</command>.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>cd dist</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make clean</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make doc</command>
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
        <procedure>
            <title>Building the &esvn; HTML Documentation</title>
            <step>
                <para>Do <command>svn update</command>.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>cd dist</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make clean</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make HTML</command>
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
        <procedure>
            <title>Building the &esvn; PDF Documentation</title>
            <step>
                <para>Do <command>svn update</command>.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>cd dist</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make clean</command>
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    <command>make fo</command>
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
        <note>
            <para>In order to transform the documentation to PDF, the HTML target must have been run
                at least once. If you have run the HTML target at least once but added images to the
                source, then the HTML target must be run again. It is not necessary to tun the HTML
                target is documentation changes did not include the addition of images.</para>
        </note>
    </sect1>
</appendix>
